冰爽礼物
往前
Ahead.
左转
Turn to the left.
冰爽礼物
从我们的家到你们的家
到卡车后面来
Step around the back of the truck.
行了
Okay.
给
Here you go.
绝命律师
第二季 第八集
我本来想带你去个
You know, I was willing to take you
更高端的地方
to a more high-end establishment.
这值得好好庆祝一番
This requires a proper celebration,
所以这一餐不算
so don't think that this counts.
这很完美了
This is perfect.
热狗屋
再说...
Besides...
我们现在得省吃俭用
we're pinching pennies now.
等我们有了稳定的收入
When we have a steady revenue stream,
每晚都要开到杰洛尼莫去吃饭
make the drive up ‭to Geronimo every night.
-在那之前...  -没错
- Till then... - ‭Yes. That.
一起实现这愿望吧
Let's make that happen.
你接下来这样
Okay, here's what ya gotta do.
马上写好你的辞职信
Type up ‭your resignation letter now --
-今晚搞定  -今晚
- I mean, tonight. - ‭Tonight?
对
‭Yeah.
当然是先吃完你的热狗...
Well, I mean, finish your hot dog first, but...
今天晚上就把辞职信放到霍华德的办公室
Now, you put that letter into Howard's office tonight.
算是在他的地盘上正式通知他
It's on his premises. You've officially given notice.
明天早上
Tomorrow morning,
他打高尔夫打得不亦乐乎时
while he's still out on the back nine chasin' his balls,
你就打给梅萨维德和其他委托人
you call Mesa Verde and your other clients,
把他们拉过来
you bring 'em along.
得比他先下手
You get to them before he does.
-不行  -什么  不
- No. ‭- What? No.
你必须现在行动
You gotta act now.
你如果用"正确方法"
Listen, ‭you do this the "Right way,"
等着当面告诉霍华德
you wait, ‭you tell Howard to his face,
他会在你说出"辞职"两字前
he'll sink his dirty hooks into Mesa Verde
就向梅萨维德伸出魔爪
before you get the words "I quit" outta your mouth.
够了吉米  很感谢你的建议
Okay, Jimmy, I appreciate the advice,
但重点是
but the whole point of this
你当你的律师  我当我的
is for you to be your kind of lawyer and me to be mine.
我要采用对我而言正确的方法
I need to find a way to do this that's right for me.
你好  金  能长话短说吗
Hey, Kim. Can we make this quick?
我有点忙不过来了
I'm kinda swamped right now.
当然  谢谢你抽空见我
Uh, sure. ‭Thanks for meeting with me.
我只需要占用几分钟
I only need a few minutes.
很好  什么事
Great. What's up?
霍华德  我们能到你办公室里说吗
Howard, ‭could we do this in your office?
拜托
Please?
再次感谢你抽空
Again, ‭thanks for taking the time.
你没必要拐弯抹角
You can just... go ahead ‭and rip off the Band-Aid.
我大概知道你来这里的目的
I have a pretty good idea why you're here.
那么  你选择去斯韦卡特和考科利
So, you're going with Schweikart and Cokely.
-什么  -我听说了
- I'm sorry? - ‭I heard.
小道消息
Through the grapevine.
我不去其他律所
I'm not going to another firm.
我要自立门户
I'm starting my own.
我打算尝试个体律师
I figured I'd try giving it a go as a solo practitioner.
我...
I, uh...
我意识到这是我该做的
I realized it was something I needed to do.
‭吉米离开戴维斯梅因律所的同一周
The week ‭Jimmy exits Davis & Main,
你也决定要离开我们
you decide to leave us?
这不可能是巧合
That can't just be happenstance.
不是
It's not.
我们会分摊支出
We're gonna be sharing expenses.
共用办公室  但是两人独立执业
One office, ‭but two separate practices.
各方面看来都...很聪明
Smart -- on several counts.
霍华德
Howard...
我希望你知道  我很珍惜在这里的时间
I want you to know ‭that I appreciate my time here.
你和律所为我做的每件事我都感激不已
I'm grateful for everything you and the firm have done for me,
特别是支付我的学费
especially the financial help with my schooling,
我准备写支票偿还剩余的贷款
and I'm ready to write a check for the remainder of the loan.
只需要会计那边给我确切金额
I just need accounting to get me that figure.
不用了  当作赠礼吧
No need. Our gift to you.
我不知道该说什么了
I don't know what to say.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你应得的
You earned it.
说实话  我有点羡慕
Tell you the truth, I'm kinda envious.
真的吗  为什么
Really? Why?
新的开始
Something about a fresh start.
想当年  我刚从法学院毕业
Back in the day, right out of law school,
我慎重考虑过自己挂牌营业
I thought long and hard about hanging up my own shingle.
-真的吗  -是的
- Oh, yeah? ‭- Yeah.
我已经准备好闯荡世界  改变世界
Oh, I was ready to take on the world, make a difference.
老爸说服了我
Dad talked me out of it.
要我加入在这里的生意
Wanted me to join the ranks here,
在律所名里再加一个"H"
throw another "H" In the firm's logo.
一切都还算顺利吧
Things work out the way they're supposed to, I guess.
金  我想告诉你  我总是对你施压
Kim, I want you to know that I always pushed you harder
是因为我相信你可以不断突破自我
because I knew that I could expect more from you.
祝你好运
Good luck to you.
谢谢
Thank you.
帮我打给梅萨维德银行的凯文·沃弛泰尔
Get me Kevin Wachtell at Mesa Verde.
取消今早所有安排
And cancel everything I had lined up this morning.
我这就打
Calling now.
不好意思
Sorry.
借过
Excuse me.
嗨  佩琪  我是金
Hi, Paige. It's Kim.
你好
Yeah, hi.
我想确认一下定在周一中午的午餐
Just checking that we're still on for lunch on Monday.
好极了  凯文也来吗
Great. And Kevin, too?
好的
Good.
在见面之前
Well, before we meet,
我有个新情况要告诉你们
there's some news you need to know about.
柠檬  水果  菠萝
希腊甜品屋
我不是安全的选择
I am not the safe choice.
安全的选择是哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
The safe choice for you would be HHM.
但我觉得我才是...
I believe, however, that I am...
正确的选择
the right choice.
为什么
Why?
你现在穿的西装是店里买的成衣吗
That suit you're wearing -- did you buy it off the rack?
别告诉我这看上去像成衣
Please don't tell me it looks like I did. ‭
如果像店里随便买的  我就不会问了
If it did, I wouldn't have asked.
那为什么你要选择订做的呢
So why do you prefer a tailor-made suit?
因为那是最适合你的
Because it fits you and you alone.
每一针每一线都是为你考虑
Because each and every stitch was fretted over with you in mind.
要么你去适合西装
Either you fit the jacket...
要么它适合你
or the jacket fits you.
如果我要一整个仓库的西装呢
What if I want ‭a whole warehouse full of suits?
那可需要很多人来缝制
That's a hell of a lot of sewing.
一个裁缝如何独自完成这项任务呢
How's one single tailor gonna get that job done?
我完全了解你们银行对于扩张的需求
I know your bank's needs in regard to this expansion inside and out.
梅萨维德作为我唯一的委托人
Having Mesa Verde as my sole client
一定会占用我全部的精力
will take up the entirety of my attention, to be sure.
但如果我不能胜任
But if this were beyond my abilities,
我就不会接
I wouldn't be ‭throwing my hat in the ring.
我不会浪费你们的时间
I would not waste your time,
以及我的时间
or mine.
你来啦  金  我们在里面
Oh, hey, Kim! We're in here!
来得正好  我正在看房
Perfect timing. ‭I was just getting the tour.
-金  这是史蒂夫  -你好
- Kim, this is Steve. - ‭Hi.
史蒂夫是这里的中介
Steve's the agent for the place.
-你好  我叫金  -见到你很高兴
- Hi. Kim. ‭- Nice to meet ya.
-金  -一切还好吗
- Hi, Kim. - ‭Everything okay?
怎么样
What do you think?
我  我觉得这是间牙医诊所吧
I, uh... I think it's a -- it's a dentist's office.
两间牙医诊室
Two offices for two dentists,
大小相同  陈设都是对称的
each the exact same size with a mirrored layout.
来
Here.
另一间就在隔壁
The other one is the next door over,
两个靠在一起
right beside this one.
就在这
Right here.
但是共用一个大厅
But they share one lobby,
一个接待区  相当平等
one reception area, so egalitarian as hell.
而且很高效
Not to mention efficient.
还有
Oh, also...
隔音墙壁
soundproof walls,
隔绝钻子啊惨叫啊之类的声音
what with the drilling and the pain and the whatnot.
还有这个地段  棒极了
And the location, I mean, holy crap.
我觉得就是这里了
I think this is the place.
金
Kim?
是啊  很好  隔音的
Yeah, it's great. Soundproofing.
史蒂夫  我们能不能单独
Hey, Steve, do you mind if we just...?
没事
Oh, please.
我出去打几个电话
I'll step outside ‭and make some phone calls.
你们慢慢说
Y'all take all the time you need.
午饭不顺利吗
Bad lunch, huh?
梅萨维德拒绝了你吗
Mesa Verde said no?
我弄不清情况了
Okay, I'm getting mixed signals here.
这是代表好的...
I-is this a good --
吉米  我搞定了
Jimmy, I got it.
-你搞定梅萨维德银行了  -是的
- You got Mesa Verde? ‭- Yes!
还没签正式文件
I mean, ‭there's nothing in writing yet,
但是午餐非常
but the lunch went...
非常顺利
It kicked ass.
当时形势确实有点危险
It was a little touch-and-go there for a moment, I'll admit,
但佩琪替我说话  帮了很大的忙
but Paige pitched in, and she really talked me up.
一等他松了口...
And then once ‭that door cracked open --
击个掌  棒极了
High five. Fantastic. ‭
我对每一个问题和担忧都准备了答案
I-I had an for answer question, every concern,
也完全没说哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所的坏话
and I did not bad-mouth HHM, not at all,
但是我很有激情
but I was, like, enthusiasm, you know,
还有私人服务  肯定也因为这个
and personal service, because that's gotta count for something.
-当然了  -就是啊
- Shit, yeah, that counts! - ‭Exactly!
毕竟
I mean, 'cause, like,
他们一开始怎么会到哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
why were they even at HHM in the first place?
还不是因为我  所以  我们走出餐馆时
Me. So, uh -- Oh, and then when we walked out of the restaurant,
凯文看不见的时候  佩琪朝我竖大拇指
when Kevin wasn't looking, Paige gives me a thumbs-up.
不是普通的竖一根
But not -- ‭not the regular thumbs-up.
是两根
The double thumbs-up.
两个  双筒枪
Two. ‭Double barrel.
砰砰  像这样
Boom, boom. Just like that.
我就知道
I knew it.
-我就知道你可以的  -真是...
- I knew you could do it! - ‭It was just...
真是太好了
God, it was perfect.
怎么了
What?
我喜欢看到你现在的样子
I just -- ‭I love seeing you like this.
我们要留着这些椅子吗
So, are we gonna keep these chairs?
你是说你喜欢这个办公室吗
Does that mean you like this office?
咱们就这么办吧
Let's do it.
没问题
Hell, yeah.
就这么办吧
Let's do it.
欧内斯托  门没锁
Ernesto, the door's open...
像往常一样
...as always.
欧内斯托
Ernesto?
是我  查克
It's me, Chuck.
霍华德  欧内斯托和你一起吗
Oh, hey, Howard, is Ernesto with you?
没有  只有我
No, it's just me.
我等文件等了一个小时了
Well, I expected a round of documents an hour ago.
我们马上要去立案了
You know ‭we've got a filing coming up.
我知道  查克
I know, Chuck.
我们很有可能...
It's very possible...
我们可能要失去梅萨维德银行了
It's likely ‭that we're losing Mesa Verde.
失去  我们刚刚才拿下他们
Losing them? We just got them.
为什么  他们打算去找谁
Well, why? Where are they going?
去找金·韦克斯勒
They're going with Kim Wexler.
她职辞了
‭She left the firm.
金辞职了
Kim left?
霍华德
Oh, Howard.
她要去哪里
Well, where's she going?
里奇·斯韦卡特那里吗
Is it Rich Schweikart?
还是里夫斯和格林律所
Or did Reeves and Green get her?
都不是  不是跳槽
Mnh. Not another firm.
她要单干了
She's going into private practice.
什么
What?
这真是...
Well, that's completely...
她要怎么自己单干呢
H-how is she going out on her own?
她为什么要单干呢
Why is she going out on her own?
没什么原因
Well, the why is the why.
至于怎么干  她正准备和吉米联手
The how is that ‭she's pooling her resources... with Jimmy.
金和我弟弟  成了合伙人吗
Kim and my brother -- partners at law?
他是斯文加利
He's Svengali.
小说《特里比》中的人物  用催眠术控制女主人公
这家伙是个催眠大师
The man is Svengali.
不管怎样  关于梅萨维德银行
At any rate, back to Mesa Verde.
我打算孤注一掷
I'm gonna try one last Hail Mary.
查克
Uh, Chuck?
-梅萨维德银行  -我听着呢
- Mesa Verde. - ‭Yes, listening.
我争取了和凯文·沃弛泰尔见面的机会
I managed to get a meeting with Kevin Wachtell.
他下午到
He's coming in this afternoon.
但我不是很清楚该遵从哪些法
But compliance law is not my strong suit.
所以如果你有任何论点论据
So if you have any details, any arguments,
现在赶快告诉我
bullet-point them for me now,
我只有一个小时的时间
'cause I got about an hour before I have to get back.
查克
Chuck?
我真的很需要你的帮助
I really need your help here.
查克
Chuck?
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我也去参加会议
I'm going to that meeting.
查克  这样也许不好吧
Chuck, I don't know if that's a good idea.
我可以的
I can do it.
我会靠意志力坚持
Force of will.
而且我已经好多了
And I've been getting better.
我知道  但是...
I know you have, but...
想想我们要传递的信息
the message that we want to send.
我懂
I know the message --
要表现得专业  而不是疯狂
that we appear professional and not crazy!
我要去开会  灯给我开着
I'm going to the meeting and the lights stay on.
大家都带着手机
Everyone keeps their phones.
一切正常就行
Everything stays, for lack of a better word, normal.
我会挺过来的
I will make it through.
请进
‭Yeah?
他们到了
They're here.
好的
Okay.
大家好
Hello, everyone.
-抱歉我来晚了  -你们好
- Sorry I was delayed. - Oh. Hi.
不不  完全没有  我们刚坐下
No, no. Not at all. We just sat down.
凯文·沃弛泰尔  佩奇·诺维克
Kevin Wachtell, Paige Novick,
这位是查尔斯·麦吉尔
this is Charles McGill.
叫我查克就好
Chuck.
-很高兴见到你们  -凯文  佩奇
- Pleasure. - Kevin. Paige.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
感谢你们两位前来
Thank you both for coming.
别担心
And don't worry.
请二位来不是来听我吹嘘HHM的
I'm not here ‭to extol the virtues of HHM.
我猜你们已经受够了
‭I'm guessing you've already had to suffer through
霍华德对于律所的强行推销了
Howard's hard sell first time around,
依我看  你们已经听够了
so you've done your time, as far ‭as I'm concerned.
才不是强行推销  那只是热情待客
What hard sell? It was enthusiasm.
我还给他们拿了饼干呢
I gave them cookies.
饼干还挺好吃的
Cookies were good, as I recall.
我今天来是想让你们放心
No, I'm here to put your minds at ease.
金·韦克斯勒
Kim Wexler is,
的确是处理梅萨维德业务的不二人选
indeed, the right choice to handle Mesa Verde.
选择她很明智
She's the obvious choice.
她年轻又聪明  前途无量
She's young, she's brilliant, she's going places.
咱们面对现实吧  霍华德
Let's face it, Howard.
她才是未来
She's the future.
像我俩这种老人家  已经过时了
Two old guys like us, we're the past.
真是让人悲伤的看法
Well, that's a sad thought.
悲伤但现实
‭Sad but true.
银行法...需要激情
Banking law... needs to be exciting.
需要下一代崛起的新秀
It needs the next generation to come along
为它注入新鲜血液
and give it a big, old kick in the seat of the pants.
真正唤醒它
Really wake it up.
我告诉你们我有多无聊
Let me tell ya how boring I am.
我靠读FEC和ISO报告来打发时间
I read FEC and ISO reports for entertainment.
没错  我能证明
He does. I can attest to that.
我想努力跟上潮流
Well, I try to stay up on things.
规则时刻在改变
The rules are changing all the time.
安然和世通出事了以后
With everything that's happened with Enron and WorldCom,
政府格外警惕
the government is extra vigilant.
现在  即便是最无心的过错
These days, the penalties for even the most honest
也可能招致毁灭性的后果
of errors can be devastating.
你需要年轻敏锐的眼光把握这些动向
You need a sharp, ‭young eye to catch that stuff.
当你已经在这个领域
I mean, when you've specialized in this kind of work
纵横了十多年  就会变得有点...
for decades on end, you tend to get kinda...
-陈腐  -陈腐
- Stale. ‭- Stale.
你会变得很陈腐
You get stale.
你会忘掉那些  譬如
You forget about things like, oh, I don't know,
《社区再投资法案》
the Community Reinvestment Act.
像梅萨维德银行这样想设新支行的银行
Any bank such as Mesa Verde looking to open a de novo branch
必须展现符合该法案的
is definitely going to need to show a healthy portfolio
健康投资组合
of CRA compliance.
当然是开玩笑了
Duh. Obviously.
我相信这方面你们肯定都做好了
You guys have all that covered, I'm sure.
《里格-尼尔州际银行和分行效益法》
Riegle-Neal Interstate Banking and Branching Efficiency Act --
真是拗口啊
there's another mouthful, huh?
无聊
Boring!
不过如果你违反该法律
Still, ‭if you were to run afoul of it,
可能得打上好几年官司
it could hold you up in court for years.
顺便  如果你们在没有我们的情况下
And by the way, uh, if that were to happen to you folks
发生这种事  不过当然不会了
as you go forward without us, which it will not, um,
霍华德在美联储有人能够帮忙处理
Howard has contacts at the Fed who could help sort things out.
一两个吧
One or two.
还有证券交易委员会对
And then there's the SEC's interpretation
《萨奥法案》302节的阐释
of Section 302 of Sarbox.
小心行事
Well, navigating that correctly
可以省下好几十万呢
could mean savings of several hundred thousand dollars.
他们很清楚呢  霍华德
They know that, Howard.
抱歉
Aapologize.
人到了一定岁数
When you reach your golden years,
就会变得有点啰啰嗦嗦
you tend ‭to get a little long-winded,
老是念叨着一些细节
ramble on and on about details.
我想说  你的银行在可靠的人手上
My point being, ‭your bank is in excellent hands.
我明白你想说什么  真的
Look, I take your point. I do.
但我要说
But I have to say,
我对韦克斯勒女士很有信心
I have complete confidence in Ms. Wexler.
你是该如此
You should.
她在我们团队中待过
She was part of our team.
她师从我们
She learned from us.
找不到比金·韦克斯勒更合适的人选了
You won't find better than Kim Wexler.
但是不管她多么优秀
But no matter how talented one individual may be,
梅萨维德的业务太重  一个人没法做
the needs of Mesa Verde are too big to handle alone.
我是不会单独处理你们今后的扩张
I wouldn't handle ‭your coming expansion alone.
所以你应该再考虑一下
Which is why you should consider, once again,
交给我们这样专业的团队
enlisting a team of professionals.
-很高兴能与你们见面  -随时恭候
- Glad we did this. - ‭Any time.
我们时刻听候你们的差遣
We are there for you day and night.
很高兴见到你  佩奇
Lovely to meet you, Paige.
我也是  谢谢
And you. Thank you.
回见  先生们
Talk soon, gentlemen.
查克  那...
Chuck, that...
真是太棒了
That was amazing.
你真是太棒了
You were fantastic.
真...查克
Trul-- Whoa. Chuck?
送我回家
Get me home.
欧尼
Ernie! ‭
撑住
Hang on.
我们还是要谢谢你
Again, we want to thank you
能够接待少校
for accommodating the Major like this.
开什么玩笑  这是我的荣幸
You kidding? It's an honor.
为了战争英雄  可以小小地破个例
For a war hero, I think we can bend the rules a wee bit.
真的很感谢你
Well, we really appreciate it.
塔尔博特少校的孙子只在城里再留一天
Major Talbott's grandsons are only in town for one more day,
他们能跟他一起分享这次经历真是太好了
so it's great they get to share this experience with him.
这将是你们永生难忘的经历
You guys are in for a real treat.
激动吗
You excited?!
是啊  很激动
Y-yeah, excited.
他们是你儿子吗
So, these are your boys?
不  我...我是他们家的律师
No, I'm -- No, I'm the family attorney.
能帮就帮一把  所以我打给了你
I just help when I can, so I called you.
很高兴为你们效劳
Well, ‭I am glad to be of service.
就是她了
And here she is.
先生们  这是菲菲
Gentlemen, meet FIFI,
世界上最后一架在任B29超级空中堡垒
the world's last ‭air-worthy B-29 Superfortress.
原本在德州基地  但是暂时飞到这儿
She's based in Texas, but she's here for a quick visit,
鼓舞飞行员的士气
just kind of a morale builder for the airmen.
不过大家现在正在吃午饭
The crew's on lunch, unfortunately.
不然我还想带你们看一下内部
Otherwise, I was gonna see about showing you the inside.
很美吧  "软糖"
Isn't she a beauty, Fudge?
就像你以前开过的飞机一样
Just like the one you used to fly.
-软糖  -没错
- Fudge? - Yep.
西奥多·"软糖"·塔尔博特少校
Major Theodore "Fudge" Talbott.
他的妈妈在战争期间
His mom used to mail him
会给他寄软糖爱心包裹
care packages of fudge during the war,
他会分给他的朋友
and he shared them with his friends.
的确是这样吧  伙计们
So that's the story. Right, guys?
-是啊  -是的
- Yes. - ‭Yeah.
先生  这一定勾起你的回忆了
Well, sir, this certainly must bring back some memories for you.
他说"太多了"
"Too many to count," He says.
我得说塔尔博特少校
I gotta say, Major Talbott...
这是我的荣幸
it's a privilege.
感谢您为国家效力
So thank you for your service.
他说"你客气了"
He says, "You're welcome."
我真羡慕你们
Boy, I envy you guys.
你们一定听过他的故事
I mean, the stories you must've heard.
有哪些不错的故事吗
You remember any good ones?
-大多是关于轰炸的  -关于轰炸
- Bombing stuff mostly. - Bombing stuff.
比如战争
Um, like, um -- like, the war.
他飞越过喜马拉雅吗
Did he fly over the Hump,
或者从印度起飞过吗
or did he take off out of India?
你没事吧  你要喝水吗
You doing okay? You need some water?
好  好的
Yes. Yes, sir.
我忘带他的水了
Oh, nuts. I forgot his water.
我可以回办公室给他拿一瓶
Oh, hey. I can run back to the office, get him a bottle.
可以吗
You could?
软糖  上尉说他要回办公室
Fudge, the captain's gonna run back to his office,
给你拿点水  好吗长官
get you some water, okay, sir?
好的  太棒了
All right. That's great.
不用着急  他没事
And there's no rush. He's gonna be fine.
我尽快回来
I'll be back ASAP.
起来  起来
Up. Up.
跟你说了什么都别说
Thought I told you not to say anything.
站到前面去  机头那  随便吧
Go stand by the front, uh, the nose, whatever.
你到底从哪找来这家伙的
Where the hell'd you find this guy?
你找不到真正的战争英雄吗
You couldn't get a real war hero?
你以为这么好找  这家伙欠我的
Yeah, like they grow on trees. So, this guy owes me.
他没钱的时候我帮他辩护
I defended him a while back when he couldn't pay.
-为他辩护什么  -怎么
- Defended him for what? - What?
你长大想当律师吗
You wanna be a lawyer when you grow up?
快搞定...
Just fix the --
公共场合自慰
Public masturbation.
简直胡说八道
Total bullshit.
好了  声音小点
All right, keep your voice down.
你没有话语权
You do not possess the power of speech.
好  开始吧
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
快点
Chop chop.
好  双手叉腰
All right, hands on hips.
行吗  表现得强壮骄傲
All right? Looking strong, looking proud, all right?
拍轰炸机  轰炸机是重点  拍它
See the bomber, okay? The bomber's the main point, so see it.
我在拍那该死的轰炸机了
I see the freaking bomber.
就不能把这家伙放国旗前吗
Couldn't just plop the dude in front of a flag?
为什么非要来这
Why'd we have to come here?
因为制作水准要高  要表演
Production value. Showmanship.
开拍了吗
You rolling?
-是的  在拍了  -在拍了
- Yeah, rolling. - Rolling.
好  开始推镜
Okay, start the dolly.
开始
And action.
你是最伟大的一代人
You're part ‭of the greatest generation.
你打过纳粹
You fought the Nazis.
打过日本人
Fought the Japanese.
-什么  -我打过日本人
- What? ‭- Fought Japanese.
我打过日本人
I fought the Japanese.
这飞机曾用于太平洋战场
This machine was used in the Pacific,
用来打日本
where the Japanese are.
你为什么不闭嘴听指示
Why don't you shut up and learn to take some direction?
一百英尺内禁烟
打的日本人
Japanese.
好  好
All right, fine.
你打过所有肮脏的轴心国
You fought all the dirty... Axis powers.
你们一群弟兄团结起来
Your band of brothers came together,
拯救了世界
and you saved the world.
你是个大英雄
You're heroic.
有点过了
Not that heroic.
表现出一点就行了
Just throw it away a little more.
好  很好
Okay, good.
爱国之情在你血液中奔驰
You've got red, white, and blue coursing through your veins.
看上面
Look up!
看见一只秃鹰直冲云霄
Picture a bald eagle soaring!
该死
‭Shit.
-怎么了  -你们继续拍
- What? - ‭Okay, just keep rolling.
-特写还是广角  -拍出好角度就行
- Tights, wides - Just get me some good angles.
好  回到原点
Okay. All right, back to one.
回到原点  软糖
Back to one. Fudge.
软糖  看这里  软糖
Fudge, right here. Fudge.
什么事  欧尼
What is it, Ernie?
吉米  我在你哥这  他情况不妙
Jimmy, man, I'm at your brother's, and he's bad.
不妙  有多不妙
Bad? How bad?
他...我说不清  就是不妙  不停发抖
He's -- I don't know. Bad, shakin'.
我从没见过他这样
I've never seen him like this.
一直告诉我别找医生
He keeps telling me not to call a doctor.
让我猜猜
Lemme guess.
他去办公室了
He's been going into the office.
是的  而且
Yeah, more and more.
他今天开了一个重要的会议
He had ‭a big meeting there today.
好的  你这么做
Okay, ‭here's what you're gonna do.
用太空毯把他裹住
Wrap him in a space blanket.
他已经裹了一层了
He's already under one.
再裹一层
Wrap him in a second one.
给他点茶  或者最好给他热点鸡汤
Make him some tea, or just, better, heat some chicken broth.
小火慢炖
Just let it simmer.
不要煮沸
Don't make it boil.
就这样  不用找医生吗
That's it? No doctor?
就这样  不用医生  他会挺过去的
That's it. No doctor. He's just gotta ride this out.
查克会没事的
Chuck'll be fine.
该死  我得走了
Oh sh-- I gotta go.
大黄  大黄
Rhubarb. Rhubarb!
傻瓜  那是暗号
Idiots, that's the signal.
让他坐轮椅上
Get him in the chair.
输氧管呢  插进你鼻子
Where's the air hose? Stick it in your nose.
快
Come on.
长官
Sir!
不用这么麻烦你们
Hey, this is not a problem.
介意我们跟你拍张照吗
Would you mind if the guys and I took a picture with you?
这对我们意义重大
It would mean a lot to us.
行  拍照  他爱拍照
Yeah, uh, p-pictures. He loves pictures.
来  给我相机
Here. Give me the camera.
-我来拍  -给你水
- I'll take it. - Here's your water.
-谢谢  -非常感谢
- Thank you, sir. - Thank you so much.
-谢谢  -没问题
- Thank you. - Yeah. Ooh, here.
行  把你推过去
All right, let's scoot ya in.
转过去
Swing ya around.
大家都站好
Okay, everybody line up?
笑
Smile.
茄子
Cheese.
你准备签了吗  来签吧
You ready to sign? Let's do this.
怎么
What?
213平方米办公空间
梅萨维德银行跑了
I lost Mesa Verde.
-什么  -我之前说服他了
- What? - ‭I had him.
我以为说服了
I thought I had him.
怎么回事
‭So what happened?
他们继续和哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所合作
They're s-sticking with HHM.
佩奇说他们今天下午过去
Paige said they went over there this afternoon
进行出于礼貌的会面
for some kind of... courtesy meeting,
反正她是这么以为  但凯文改变想法了
or so she thought, ‭and Kevin got his head turned.
-霍华德说服的吗  -不
- By Howard? - ‭No.
查克
Chuck.
吉米  我得问
Jimmy, I have to ask.
你还想这么做吗
You still up for doing this?
你说租下办公室吗
What? You mean getting the office?
这一切
All of it.
我想我们也许得
I think maybe we need to...
放慢脚步  好好...
slow down and really, you know...
考虑这事
think about this.
等等
Wait. Whoa.
-都没变  -都没变吗
- Nothing's changed. - N-nothing's changed?
我们马上要签下非常贵的租约
We're about to sign a very expensive lease
但一大笔收入已经不翼而飞了
after a very sizable chunk of income just went flying out the window.
这就是团队的意义
That's why we're a team.
这种事总会发生
Something like this happens --
你帮我  我帮你
you're there to help me, I'm there to help you.
还会有梅萨维德这种大客户的
There will be other Mesa Verdes.
你还是想继续吗
So you still wanna do this?
吉米...
Jimmy...
我完全按你说的做
I did everything you said,
但他并未好转
but he's not getting any better.
你做得很好  欧尼
You did good, Ernie.
谢谢
Thanks.
你回家休息一下吧
Why don't you, uh, ‭go home and get some sleep?
我来接手
I'll take over.
他说想让我留下
He told me he wanted me to stay.
没关系  我来了
It's okay. I'm here now.
你下次见霍华德时
And, uh, next time you see Howard,
告诉他你要大大加薪
tell him you need a raise -- a big one.
查克  兄弟
Chuck, buddy?
感觉如何
‭How you feeling?
梅萨维德
你好
Hey, how's it going?
我需要美工刀  尺子  要木头的
I need an X-ACTO knife, a ruler -- wood, please --
锤磨机优质纸  二十磅  五百张
Hammermill Premium paper -- 20 pound, one ream --
还有固体胶
and a glue stick.
我要用最好的复印机
Oh, and point me to your best copier.
-最好的复印机  -没错  最好的复印机
- Best copier? - ‭Yeah. Best copier.
快  时间很紧
C'mon. Di di mau.
这个礼拜  十分古怪*
*Been a strange old week
未做之事  遇见之人*
*With the stuff you didn't do and the people that you meet
挖掘信息  就像拔牙*
*And digging up the words like pulling teeth
一副面孔  一个数字*
*Got a face, a number
以及她使用的化名*
*And a name that she goes under
也许这已相当不错*
*I guess there's plenty worse place to be
那你为何不干*
*So why don't you do it
*Yeah, why don't you do it
多点享乐  又有何妨*
*Ain't no harm in having just a bit more fun
无论自己  喜不喜欢*
*Whether you like it or not
永远别摆  一副臭脸*
*Make no place for dragging down your face
你该知道这是最好的结果*
*Don't you know it's the best one that you got
那你为何不干*
*So why don't you do it
*Yeah, why don't you do it
那你为何不干*
*Why don't you do it, ooh
*Why don't you do it
抢劫银行*
*Break that bank
你可能一无所获*
*You never know, you might draw blanks
然后还被绳之以法*
*Then again, it might sort you out
那你为何不干  为何不干  为何不干*
*So why don't you do it, do it, do it, do it, do it, do it
干啊*
*Do it
他起来了
He emerges.
下午好
Good afternoon.
下午了吗
Is it afternoon?
欧内斯托人呢
Where's Ernesto?
他应该留下来陪我的
He was supposed to stay with me.
别怪欧尼
Don't get mad at Ernie.
他花了一天中最好的时间
He spent the better part of a day
欣赏你烤土豆[裹锡纸]的表演
watching you do your impression of a baked potato.
我让他回家去睡会
I told him to go home, get some shut eye.
你饿吗
‭You hungry?
除了饼干还想吃点什么吗
You want something besides crackers?
不用  我没事
No, I'm fine.
等我的胃不难受了我自己弄点东西吃
I'll fix myself something after my stomach settles.
在外面待这么久
Really doing a number on yourself,
真把你伤得不轻
spending so much time out of the house.
你就非得这么干  是吧
You just had to do it, huh?
不能眼看着金挖走梅萨维德银行
Couldn't stand ‭to let Kim have Mesa Verde.
就非得从她手上抢走
You had to swipe it from her.
我没有抢走任何东西
I didn't swipe anything.
我们只是留住委托人
We retained our client.
你和霍华德甚至都没听说过这个银行
You and Howard never even heard about Mesa Verde
是金把它捧到你们面前的
till Kim brought it to ya on a red velvet pillow.
我要去冲个澡  还有一堆工作要处理
I need a shower, and I've got a ton of work to do.
如果你想吵架  吉米
So if you're lookin' for a fight, Jimmy,
我实在没心情和你吵
I just don't have it in me.
吉米
Jimmy.
谢谢你留下来陪我
Thanks for stayin' with me.
我们之间有积怨未解
I know we have our issues,
但是  如果我俩换一下
but if things were reversed,
我希望你知道  我也会一样待你
I hope you know that I would do the same for you.
干得真不错
You're doing a great job.
你以前做过这个吗
You done this before?
没有  没做过这样的
No, not like this,
不过我们在学校里学过分数
but we learned about fractions in school.
是吗  什么分数
You did? What fractions?
二分之一英寸  四分之一英寸
1/2 inch, 1/4 inch,
八分之一英寸  十六分之一英寸
1/8 inch, 1/16 inch.
你知道吗  我得承认
You know, I gotta tell ya,
我在你这个年纪的时候可没你聪明
you are much smarter than I was when I was your age.
或许是你老师教得不够好
Maybe you needed better teachers.
有可能
That could be.
能让我来钻吗
Can I do the drill now?
你答应了的
You promised.
是呀  我是答应了
I did, didn't I?
好了  过来
Okay, get up here.
用重型工具的时候
Now, you're gonna have to wear these
得戴上这个
if you're gonna handle the heavy machinery.
你怎么不戴
W-why don't you have to wear them?
因为爷爷是大人  大人就可以变笨
Because Pop-Pop's a grown-up, and grown-ups get to be stupid.
好了  戴上
Now, put them on.
好的
All right.
这个很重  所以我来拿着
Now, I'm gonna hold this because it's heavy,
我说按扳柄的时候你就按  行吗
but you pull the trigger when I say so, okay?
把手放上来
Now get your hand on it.
好了  拿好了吗
All right, you got it?
准备好了
Ready.
好的  准备  按
All right, ready...set...pull.
干得好
Good job.
能再来几次吗
Can we do more? ‭
你帮我放好
You line them up for me.
在家吗
Hello?!
我们在后面
We're back here.
这是在干什么
Wow. What's all this?
我们在做一个特制软管
We're making a special hose.
特制软管啊  看出来了
Yeah, that's a special hose, all right.
我每隔四分之三英寸做一个记号
I made marks every 3/4 inch,
然后爷爷在下面垫上一块木头
then Pop-Pop put a piece of wood down
这样就不会划到桌子了
so he doesn't ruin his table.
然后我们在标记号的地方钻孔
Then we line up a drill, put the hole on the "X."
我要给外面的杜鹃花做个滴灌管
I needed a soaker ‭for the rhododendrons out back.
好了  爷爷要自己完成工作了
Well, Pop-Pop's gonna have to finish his project on his own,
我们得走了
because we have to go.
可我们还没做完呢
But we're not done yet.
没事  我会做好的
No, I'll finish up.
小公主  你已经帮了我很大的忙了
But you, young lady, were a big help.
抱抱
Give me a hug.
爱你  宝贝
Love you, girl.
-我也爱你  -谢谢  麦克
- Love you. ‭- Thanks, Mike.
对了  你周五还是有空的吧
Oh, you still good for Friday?
当然
Absolutely.
我到时候再找个东西让她玩
I'll think of another project by then.
太好了  再见
Fantastic. Bye.
再见
Bye.
我午餐已经约了人了
I have a lunch date already.
-推了  -不能推
- Well, break it. - ‭I cannot break it.
能别碰我吗
Will you take your hands off me?
你以为你是正骨医生吗
What are you playing, osteopath?
别激动
Temper, temper.
沃尔特  你已经不是我的丈夫了
Oh, listen, Walter, you are no longer my husband
也不再是我的老板
and no longer my boss.
我以后也不会再为你工作了
And you're not gonna be my boss.
如果你满足于当编辑和记者
Well, it would've worked out if you'd been satisfied
事情就不会这样  可你就不
with just being editor and reporter, but not you.
你非要嫁给我  毁了这一切
You had to marry me, spoil everything.
我不满足  那是我求的婚咯
I wasn't satisfied? I suppose I proposed to you.
差不多就是  你连着两年
Well, you practically did, making goo-goo eyes at me
整天对我送秋波  直到我松口
for two years until I broke down.
"啊  沃尔特"
"Oh, Walter."
而且我那晚是喝醉了才向你求的婚
And I still claim I was tight the night I proposed to ya.
如果你是个绅士
If you'd have been a gentleman,
就该忘了那晚的事  可你就不
you'd have forgotten all about it, but not you.
你竟敢
Why, you!
你眼力不如以往了
You're losing your eye.
你以前扔得可比这准多了
You used to be able to pitch better than that.
你好  是的  怎么了  斯威尼
Hello? Yeah. What? Sweeney?
有什么我能帮忙的吗
Well, what can I do for ya?